-- Usagi Drop 01 --
What was that?
Kawachi
Ok, sure.
I just woke up.
Oh, I see. Got it.
There's nothing to worry about.
We'll talk things over with them early next week, okay?
See you.
My grandfather, from my mother's side, passed away last night.
Was that him I was dreaming about earlier? And my mom?
I heard he sort of distanced himself from the rest of the family.
The one time I come back home is for a funeral...
Presented by:
Taka Fansubs
I'm home.
Oh, Daikichi? That was quick.
You can put your bags in Grandpa's room.
Okay.
I saw a young girl out in the garden.
Is she Haruko's?
No, that's not Reina-chan.
Then who is she?
Sheesh, this kitchen is hopeless.
What should we do now?
At 79, he lived a good, long life, right?
That girl is Grandpa's illegitimate child.
What?!
She's Grandpa's child?!
He never said a word about it.
And we don't even know where his lover is.
His lover? He was 79, you know!
Sheesh, I can't decide if it's embarrassing or just shameful.
So that girl is your sister?
Which makes her my aunt.
There's nothing funny about this!
You're 30 years old! You know
better than to make jokes like that!
You really did die peacefully, didn't you, Grandpa?
How much should I give?
It doesn't matter. Any amount will help.
I know that, but isn't there some usual amount people give?
Really, any amount will help.
Though recently, sutra recitations and the giving of a posthumous name have become quite expensive.
She recommended between 40,000 and 50,000 yen.
That's quite a lot.
Good to see you all after so long.
Daikichi, it's sure been a while.
Have you been busy?
Yeah, I guess.
So busy you can't visit your own mother?
You weren't even here for New Year's.
Here.
Wait, Reina!
Stop it, Reina!
Haruko.
Oh, Dai-chan, it's good to see you.
Mama!
Reina!
I've got you now!
Now be a good girl and stay quiet.
No, I don't want to!
What is it?
Nothing.
You just look a lot like Grandpa when he was young.
So Daikichi, did you hear?
Yeah, my mom told me.
But is it really true?
I know my older brother felt lonely living alone, but...
He left behind a child care book.
It says her name is Rin.
Still, how could a 79 year-old man do this?
Well, regardless of whether he could have done it or not, you've gotta hand it to him.
Daikichi, would you bring the cushions from the closet, please?
Okay.
What's up?
Hey, wanna trade?
Wait! Just leave it like that.
I did it!
Look! Look!
Don't run, Reina!
Wow, that's great!
Isn't it pretty?
Very! You sure are good at cat's cradle, Reina-chan.
Now try a four-step ladder!
Here, Reina-chan, let me show you.
Poop bomb!
Come back here, Reina!
Wake up, Uncle.
Go ahead and get some sleep.
I'll watch over the incense.
Oh, okay.
Hey, don't sleep here!
Let's rest over there.
What about the incense?
Daikichi said he'll watch it.
Come on now.
Watch over my older brother, please.
Go sleep over there too.
I'm fine.
You don't look fine.
Kaga
Souichi
Everyone, please offer your final farewells.
Rest in peace.
Brother...
I'll see you again very soon.
Come, Reina.
Okay!
Go say bye to Grandpa.
Okay.
Flower garden!
Stop that!
No! I want to make a flower garden!
I want to!
You should say goodbye too.
Put this on Grandpa.
Hey!
A bellflower?
Grandpa's favorite flower...
Grandpa will love this flower the most.
He won't wake up?
No, he won't.
You really are Grandpa's child, aren't you?
Maternity and Child
Care Handbook
Kaga Souichi
Yoshii Masako
Rin
Where did this "Yoshii Masako" go?
I don't know what the point in trying to find
someone who left their child and ran away is.
She has no sense of responsibility.
My brother was also really stubborn about it.
Be careful!
That girl can't talk!
It's such a pain!
She hasn't even lost her baby teeth!
She can talk!
And she's not a pain!
No, she can't talk!
It's so boring being with her!
Here, take all of these and go away.
It's like you own a candy shop!
Sorry about that, Dai-chan.
Later on is one thing,
but who's going to watch over that girl right now?
I can't. I'm at the store all day.
I would if she was a more proper girl.
Not to mention she has a hard time talking.
Mom.
You're always at home. Couldn't you watch her for a bit?
Of course not!
I'm not as free as you think!
Besides, do you have any idea how hard it is to raise a child?
Don't you know how much I've had to sacrifice over the years?
I'd feel bad for the girl if she was looked after half-heartedly.
Wasn't the point of this meeting to
figure out who would look after Rin?
It's not like you have any intention of taking her in, do you, Brother?
Be realistic.
We're not even sure that she's really Grandpa's child.
See? You haven't even considered everything.
Anyway, I say we try putting her in a care facility as soon as possible.
What's wrong?
Rin!
Wanna come stay with me?
Hold on, Daikichi!
Brother?!
Old man, I'm hungry.
Old man?!
Don't call me that!
You're my aunt, you know!
Good?
Yes.
You want more?
There's only rice left.
I'll make rice balls then.
There's nothing left to fill it with.
Salt!
Salt?
Hey, it's still hot!
Careful!
It'll make it taste softer.
Here you go, Grandpa.
I mean, Daikichi!
Daikichi doesn't sound right either.
It's great.